Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records apap401
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Death Penalty and the Catholic Church, 1989-2015
  - Ministry Against Death Penalty
    - CMN Printed Materials Inventory List, 2012 July
    - Catholic Mobilizing Network to End Use of the Death Penalty "Report to CSJ Ministry Against the Death Penalty Board", 2012 August
    - Activities of Director of Catholic Networks & Organizations, Cathy Jarboe, 2012 November
    - Activities of CMN Hispanic Outreach, Ilaria Buonriposi, 2012 November
    - Activities of Vicki Schieber and St. Mary's University CMN Office, 2012 November
    - Catholic Mobilizing Network to End Use of the Death Penalty, Report to CSJ Ministry Against the Death Penalty Board, 2012 November
    - Report on the Death Penalty, Ruthman Kettman, CSJ, 2012 November
    - Ministry Against the Death Penalty, Ohio Update, 2013 May
    - Dead Man Walking School Theatre Project Report, Play Project Inquiry Sheet, 2012
    - Proposed FY Budget for Ministry Against the Death Penalty, 2013
    - Ministry Against the Death Penalty Board Roster, 2012-2013
    - Ministry Against the Death Penalty Staff Roster, 2012-2013
    - Dead Man Walking School Theatre Project Report, Business Plan Going Forward, 2012-2013
    - Activities of CMN Office, Washington, DC, 2012 February-2012 November
    - Congregation of St. Joseph Ministry Against the Death Penalty "CMN - Profit & Loss Budget Performance", 2012 June-2013 June
    - Congregation of St. Joseph Ministry Against the Death Penalty "MADP- Profit & Loss Budget Overview", 2012 June-2013 June
    - Congregation of St. Joseph Ministry Against the Death Penalty, Consolidates Statements of Activties, 2012 July-2013 March
    - Congregation of St. Joseph Ministry Against the Death Penalty, PLAY-Profit & Loss Budget Overview, 2012 July-2013 June
    - Ministry Against the Death Penalty, Ohio Report, 2012 August-2012 November
    - Ministry Against the Death Penalty, Annual Board Meeting Agenda, 2012 November 16-2012 November 17
    - Report from Helen to MADP Board Part 2: Ideas for New Initiatives, 2012 November 16-2012 November 17
    - Report from Helen to MADP Board Part 1, 2012 November 16-2012 November 17
    - Ministry Against the Death Penalty Board Meeting, Minutes, 2012 November 16-2012 November 17
    - Highlights of CMN Activities, 2013 January-2013 April
- KCDAP Meetings and Events, 2005-2015
  This series contains documents about the planning, execution, and results of the 2012 Death Penalty Abolition Strategy Summit, Sister Helen Prejean visits, KCADP meeting minutes and agendas, and presentations both given to and presented by KCADP members.
  This series contain four subseries.
  - Events, 2007-2011
    - Meeting with Herald-Leader Editorial Board, 2011 November 2
    - Invitation to Meet Wendell Berry, 2011
    - "Race to Execution" Watch Part Event, 2007
    - University of Louisville Peace Studies Program Event, 2011 September 11
  - Presentations, 1989-2014
    - Meeting Minutes, Lexington Chapter, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Meeting Minutes, North Kentucky Chapter, 1987-2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Meeting Minutes, Louisville Chapter, 1989-2003 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - The Penalty of Death Presentation by the Kentucky Department of Public Advocacy, 2011 June 29
    - Recording of Bryan Stevenson at ACLU Freedom Dinner, 2012 October 27
    - Remarks for Randy Steidl at BCTC, 2012 November 26
    - Thank You Letter to Pat Delahanty from Donna Schneweis, 2013 February 8
    - Death Row Innmate Groupings of Severity of Crime, 2013 February 12
    - Information for Editorial Boards, 2013 November 18
    - Department of Public Advocacy Press Release for House Bill 330, 2014 February 4
    - Presentation for EKU with Kristen Bollig, 2013 September
    - Status of Death Penalty in Kentucky, 2013 November
    - Death Row Exonerated Inmates, 2014 August
  - Death Penalty Abolition Strategy Summit, June 14 2012 - June 15 2012
    - 2012 Strategy Meeting
    - Notes at What Worked in New Mexico, 2009 July 5
    - Presentation for Moratorium on the Death Penalty in Kentucky by the American Bar Association, 2011 December 13
    - Outstanding Questions, 2012 May 19
    - Presentation for Death Penalty Summitt, 2012 June 12
    - Death Penalty Abolition Strategy Summit Draft Session, 2012 June 14-2012 June 15
    - Death Penalty Abolition Strategy Summit Notes, 2012 June 14-2012 June 15
    - Confidentiality Policy for the Abolition 2025 Campaign, 2012 June 14-2012 June 15
    - Equal Justice USA "Conservatives are Concerned about the Death Penalty" Fact Sheet, 2012 June 14-2012 June 15
    - Death Penalty Abolition Strategy Summit Agenda, 2012 June 14-2012 June 15
    - Death Penalty Abolition Strategy Summit Notes- Confidential, 2012 June 14-2012 June 15
    - Religious Leaders Talking Points, 2012 September 20
    - Kentucky Council of Churches Letter to Govenor Beshear, 2012 September 24
    - Presbyterian Church (USA) Letter to Govenor Beshear, 2012 September 26
    - "Kentucky's Egregious Death Penalty" Article, The New York Times, 2012 October 24
    - Agenda for Planning Phone Call, 2012 November 1
    - NCADP Statement on Narrow Defeat of Prop 34 in California, 2012 November 7
    - Prop 34 Suggested Talking Points, 2012 November 7
    - Kentucky Comission on Human Rights Resolution Opposing the Death Penalty, 2012 November 7
    - Sample Bridge Messages for State Campaign Leaders in Response to California's Prop 34 Vote, 2012 November 8
    - "Is there a political plan B for the bishops" Article, National Catholic Reporter, 2012 November 11
    - "Innocence Lost in New Jersey" Article of Exonerated and Executed Death Row Innmate Larry Griffin, 2005
    - List of New Legislators, 2005
    - Notes at What Worked in New Jersey, 2008
    - Notes at What Worked in Maryland, 2012
  - Helen Prejean Visit
    - Archdiosce of New Orleans Bishop Letter of Good Standing for Sister Helen Prejean, 2012 March 16
    - Letter Inviting Kentucky Council of Churches to Meet Sister Helen Prejean, 2013 November 21
    - Sister Helen Prejean Louisville Event Graphic, 2013 December 5
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Form Completed, 2013 December 5
    - Sister Helen Prejean Event Postcard, 2013 December 5
    - Sister Helen Prejean Itenerary, 2014 October 23-2014 October 26
    - Mary Moss Thank You Letter, 2014 November 28
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Contract, 2015 July 14
    - Sister Helen Prejean Lexington Visit Flyer, 2015 November 10
    - Sister Helen Prejean DeSales High School Visit Flyer, 2015 November 11
    - Letter to Kentucky Legislator from Sister Helen Prejean, 2013 November
    - Sister Helen Prejean Agenda Update Form, 2013
    - Sister Helen Prejean Biographical Information, 2013
    - Sister Helen Prejean "Dead Man Walking" Book Flyer, 2013
    - Sister Helen Prejean Flyer Regarding Catholic Mobilizing Network, 2013
    - Sister Helen Prejean One Page Form For Speaking Completed, 2013
    - Sister Helen Prejean Biographical Information, 2014
    - Sister Helen Prejean Information Regarding Book, 2014
    - Sister Helen Prejean Photograph, 2014
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Form Completed, 2014
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Form Instructions, 2014
    - Sister Helen Prejean Website eNews Post, 2014
    - Sister Helen Prejean Biographical Information, 2015
    - Sister Helen Prejean Book Packing Information, 2015
    - Sister Helen Prejean Information Regarding Book, 2015
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Form Blank, 2015
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Form Completed, 2015
    - Sister Helen Prejean Speaking Engagement Form Instructions, 2015
  - KCDAP Meeting Agendas
    - Meeting Minutes, Lexington Chapter, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Meeting Minutes, North Kentucky Chapter, 1987-2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Meeting Minutes, Louisville Chapter, 1989-2003 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Legislative Activities, 1992-2023
  This series contains documents relating to legislative efforts made to abolish the death penalty in the state of Kentucky, including: legislation for the years 2011, 2012, 2015, 2016, 2019, 2020, 2022, and 2023 and "Abolition Now!" for the years 2002, 2003, 2004, and 2006, records relating to abolishing the death penalty due to the high cost of tax payers, records relating to sentencing because of racial bias, documents regarding mental ineptitude as a reason not to execute, documents relating to sentencing and appeals of death row inmates, court documents, execution protocol, the Innocence Project, law enforcement booklets, letters to legislators, notes from KCADP member meetings with legislators, and studies regarding the death penalty.
  This series contains twenty-four subseries.
  - 2013 Legislation
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky Franklin Circuit Court, Civil Action No. 04-CI-1094, 2013 December 5
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky Franklin Circuit Court, Civil Action No. 06-CI-574, 2013 December 5
    - Disposition of Kentucky Death Eligible Cases (2000-2010) Where the Death Penalty Was Sought (Entire State) Graphic, 2013
  - 2021 Legislation
    - Legislative Strategy for Passing Severely Mentally Ill Bill, 2021 September 13
  - Abolition 2000, 1999
    - Abolition 2000, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 2011 Legislation
    - The State of New Hampshire v. et al, Order on Motions to Dismiss and Objections, 2005 August 12
    - Talking Points, Mental Disabilities and the Death Penalty, 2007 March 28
    - Mentally Ill Man Recieves Life on Appeal, 2008 June 3
    - Death Penalty- Severely Mentally Ill Act, Draft, 2008 June 27; 2008 July 21
    - Art Shechet Comment on 2nd Draft Language, 2008 August 19
    - Cover Story for Louisville Eccentric Observer "Crazy and Condemned- Kentucky Could Be the First State to Ban Executions of the Severely Mentally Ill", 2008 September 3
    - Courier-Journal.com Op-Ed "From Bad to Worse", 2008 September 10
    - Kentucky Mental Health Coalition, General Membership Meeting Minutes, 2008 September 10
    - General Assembly of North Carolina, Bill Draft 2009-LH-2 (v.7), Draft, 2008 September 11
    - CommonDreams.org News Center Press Release "Use of Death Penalty Declines in 2006, Public Now Favors Life without Parole, Lehtal Injection Challenges Lead to Fewest Executions in a Decade, Death Sentences at 30-Year Low", 2008 October 13
    - Death Penalty Resolution, Item for Board Consideration from Carol Carrithers NAMI KY Executive Director, 2008 October 25
    - Item for Board Consideration from Carol Carrithers, NAMI KY Executive Director, 2008 October 25
    - Conference Call on Mental Illness and the Death Penalty, 2008 November 21
    - Kentucky Mental Health Coalition, General Membership Meeting Agenda, 2008 December 3
    - Capital Procedure/ Severe Mental Disability Presentation, 2008 December 4
    - Capital Procudure/Severe Mental Disability Pamphlet, 2008 December 4
    - Resolution of the Promptness Subcommittee of the Death Penalty Study Committee, 2008 December 4
    - Kentucky Coalition for Responsible Lending Lending Fact Sheet, 2009 January 12
    - Email Message Regarding: GBMI v. Death Penalty Preclusion for the Severely Mentally Ill, 2009 January 22
    - Supreme Court of Pennsylvania, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania v. James W. Vandivner, 2009 January 23
    - Legislative Research Commission Letter to Director Robert Sherman Regarding Cost of the Death Penalty in KY since 1976, 2009 February 2
    - Mental Illness ACT Language, 2009 February 4
    - "Act Now!" Urge Representatives to Co-Sponsor House Bill 446, 2009 February 15
    - Death Penalty-Template for Mental Illness Death Penalty Supporters, 2009 February 15
    - House Bill 446, an ACT related to Mental Illness, 2009 February 15
    - Kentucky and Guilty But Mentally Ill, Defendant Can Still Be Executed, 2009 February 15
    - Mentally Ill Bill Explanation, 2009 February 15
    - Mentally Ill Bill Text with Explanation, 2009 February 15
    - KY and Guilty but Mentally Ill; Defendant can still be Executed, 2009 February 15
    - Report of the Council to the Membership of The Law Institute On the Matter of the Death Penalty, without Appendage, 2009 April 15
    - Report of the Council to the Membership of The Law Institute On the Matter of the Death Penalty, 2009 April 15
    - Definitions for Mentall Illness and Insanity Bill, 2009 June 16
    - Email RE: Request for information Regarding an Article for "Mental Health Weekly", 2009 July 14
    - SMI-Death Penalty Conference Call, 2009 August 5
    - Death Penalty Item for Consideration Template for Mental Illness Death Penalty, 2009 September 28
    - Letter to Editors from Reps. David Floyd and Darryl Owens, 2009 October 15
    - Kentucky Coalition for Responsible Lending Letterhead, 2009 December 1
    - Catholics @ The Capitol Proposed Master Calendar of Regional 2010-11 Events, 2010-2011
    - New York Times Article "Group Gives Up Death Penalty Work", 2010 January 5
    - Jhouse Bill 16 Web Version, 2010 January 6
    - Kentucky Legislature Logo, 2010 January 6
    - Preclude the Use of the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, 2010 January 8
    - Kentucky Coalition for Responsible Lending Fact Sheet Bill Keypoints, 2010 January 19
    - House Bill 16: An Act Related to Mental Illness, Urgent Action Request, 2010 February 4
    - Letter to Kentucky Lawmakers, Draft, 2010 February 10
    - House Bill 16 Handout, 2010 February 11
    - House Bill 16 Handout, 2010 February 12
    - House Bill 16- House and Senate Anticipated Vote, 2010 February 13
    - House Bill 16 Handout, 2010 February 13
    - House Bill 16 Handout, 2010 February 24
    - PayDay Loan District Court List, 2010 March 1
    - Letter to Govenor Brewer Regarding Senate Bill 1070, 2010 April 19
    - Immigration Reform DREAM Act, Catholic Conference of Kentucky, 2010 May 16
    - Our Sunday Visitor News Analysis "Answering Tough Questions About immigration", 2010 May 16
    - The New York Times Op-Ed "The Cheap Cost of Cheating the Lowest Paid", 2010 June 25
    - Arizona Penalty for Not Paying Wages, 2010 July 2
    - "Not in Our State: What Community-Based Organizations Can Do to Combat SB 1070 CopyCat Legislation" Tool Kit for Advocates, 2010 July 1
    - Kentucky Forward Coalition Meeting Notes, 2010 July 14
    - Arizona Catholic Conference Press Release "Arizona Roman Catholic Bishops' Statement on U.S. District Court Judge Susan Bolton's Ruling on SB 1070", 2010 July 28
    - Joint Judiciary Lists for Constant Contact, 2010 July 29
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky, Payday Loan Flyer, 2010 August 2
    - Kentucky General Assembly, Judiciary Committee Meeting, 2010 August 11
    - Commonwealth Attorneys List, 2010 August 24
    - Elected Commonwealth Attorney Contact Information, 2010 August 25
    - Draft for Cathy on SMI Hearing for Legislators, 2010 August 26
    - Kentucky Forward Coalition Meeting Notes and Agenda, 2010 September 28
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky to Pastors and Pastorial Leaders, 2010 October 1
    - Guttmacher Institute State Policies in Brief, Counseling and Waiting Periods for Abortion, 2010 October 1
    - An ACT relating to the Full Disclosure of Public Safety with Ultrasound Language, 2010 October 4
    - An ACT relating to the Full Disclosure of Public Safety, Tanya Pullen Version, 2010 October 4
    - Invite from the Bishop for Catholics @ the Capitol: Hopkinsville Regional Gathering, 2010 October 5
    - kentucky League for Educational Alternatives and Catholic Conference of Kentucky Tax Credits Flyer, 2010 October 6
    - Letter to Ron Tabak rom Pat Delahanty, 2010 October 7
    - Email RE: Information for Catholics @ Capitol: Hopkinsville Region, 2010 October 8
    - Catholics @ the Capitol in Edmonton Bulletin and Media Release, 2010 October 8
    - Kentucky Registered Legislative Agents, 2010 October 11
    - Kentucky Registered Legislative Employers, 2010 October 11
    - Catholics @ the Capitol: Faithful Citizenship Flyer, 2010 October 13
    - Informed Consent Statute 311, 2010 October 20
    - Archdiocese of Louisville US and KY Legislators & Parishes by Regions, 2010 October 23
    - Catholic Diocese of Lexington Letter from Reverend W. Gainer, 2010 October 29
    - Catholic Diocese of Lexington Letter from Reverend W. Gainer to Fellow Priests, 2010 October 29
    - "SB 1070 Support Our Law Enforcement and Safe Neighborhood Act", 2010 November 3
    - Catholics @ the Capitol: Hopkinsville Region Agenda, 2010 November 6
    - Catholics @ the Capitol: Hopkinsville Region Flyer, 2010 November 6
    - Catholics @ the Capitol 2010-2011: Faithful Citizenship in the Diocese of Lexington, Bluegradd West Deanery, 2010 November 7
    - Tabling -Catholics @ the Capitol 2010-2011: Faithful Citizenship in the Diocese of Lexington, Bluegrass West Deanery, 2010 November 7
    - Catholic Charities, Catholics @ the Capitol Edmonton Event Pamphlet, 2010 November 7
    - Catholic Charities, Catholics @ the Capitol Edmonton Event Flyer, 2010 November 7
    - Catholics @ the Capitol in Edmonton Evaluation, 2010 November 7
    - Testimony before the Kentucky Consumer Advisory Committee, 2010 November 9
    - Tabling -Catholics @ the Capitol 2010-2011: Faithful Citizenship in the Diocese of Lexington, Bluegrass East Deanery, 2010 November 13
    - Catholics @ the Capitol at St Catharine College Evaluation, 2010 November 14
    - Informed Consent Legislation Flyer, Catholic Conference of Kentucky, 2010 November 15
    - "Response from Experts" Document, 2010 November 15
    - American Bar Association, Section of Indivdual Rights and Responsibilities Criminal Justice Section 122A, 2010 November 16
    - Unofficial Copy of Act Relating to the Exclusion of Abortion Coverage for Health Insurance Exchanges, 2010 November 17
    - Catholics @ the Capitol Letter to Representative Bell Regarding Edmonton Gathering, 2010 November 22
    - Catholics @ The Capitol – KY General Assembly 2011 Short Session Report, 2010 November 22
    - Wheeler- KY and Guilty But Mentally Ill Defendant can Still Be Executed Document, 2010 November 22
    - Public Policy Arguments Against SB 1070 Copy-Cat Legislation, Draft, 2010 December 7
    - Catholic Charities, Catholics @ the Capitol Bradenburg Event Pamphlet, 2010 December 7
    - Catholic Charities, Catholics @ the Capitol Bradenburg Event Flyer, 2010 December 7
    - Alert on DREAM for US Senate, 2010 December 8
    - Tabling- Catholics @ the Capitol: Faithful Citizenship in the Diocese of Lexington, Big Sandy/ Licking Deanery, 2010 December 11
    - Tabling- Catholics @ the Capitol: Faithful Citizenship in the Diocese of Lexington Mountain East Deanery, 2010 December 11
    - Busting the Dream Act Myths: USCCB/MRS Response to the Most Cited DREAM Myths, 2010 December 13
    - Proposed Bill from Last Year's Text, AN ACT relating to pre-settlement funding providers and making an appropriation therefor, 2010 December 15
    - Herald-Leader Editorial "Wiliams' Cynical Ploy Immigration", 2010 December 19
    - Courier-Journal.com "Senator David Williams Unveils Immigration Reform Bill", 2010 December 29
    - Informed Consent Senatge Bill 9, 2010 December 29
    - Courier-Journal.com "Ky. Lawmakers Diverge on Illegal Immigration", 2010 December 30
    - Courier-Journal.com "Opponents Raise Concerns About Proposed State Immigration Measure", 2011 January 4
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky Letter to Senator Regarding Immigration Reform, 2011 January 4
    - Kentucky.com "Opponents say Ky. Immigration Bill Goes Further than Arizona Law", 2011 January 4
    - USA Today "Ky. Republicans file immigration bill as promised", 2011 January 4
    - Kentucky.com Article "Put Interest Cap on Payday Loans", 2011 January 4
    - Courier-Journal.com Editorial "A hateful bill", 2011 January 5
    - Testimony for Senate Judiciary Committee in Opposition to Senate Bill 6, An Act Relating to Unauthorized Aliens, 2011 January 6
    - USA Today "Senate Panel OKs Crackdown on Illegal Immigrants", 2011 January 6
    - Courier-Journal.com "Kentucky Senate Panel Backs Immigration Enforcemnt Bill", 2011 January 6
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky Press Release "Catholic Conference Will Continue to oppose Sentae Bill 6", 2011 January 7
    - Presbyterian Church U.S.A. Letter to Kentucky Legislators, 2011 January 7
    - Kentucky.com "Immigration Enforcement Bill Heads to Kentucky Senate", 2011 January 7
    - Courier-Journal.com "Ky. Senate Passes Crackdown on illegal Immigrants", 2011 January 7
    - Courier-Journal.com "Senate Approves Tough Immigration Bill", 2011 January 7
    - Courier-Journal.com "Organizations to Oppose Immigration Bill", 2011 January 8
    - Kentucky.com "GOP Leaders Push Immigration Bill, Other Priorities Through State Senate", 2011 January 8
    - bgDaily News.com "Catholics at the Capitol focuses on Immigration", 2011 January 8
    - Courier-Journal.com "Organizations Gather to Oppose Immigration Bill", 2011 January 8
    - Tabling- Catholics @ the Capitol: Faithful Citizenship in the Diocese of Lexington Mountain West Deanery, 2011 January 8
    - Kentucky.com "Immigration Bill Not Worth the Costs", 2011 January 9
    - Catholic Legal Immigration Network Inc. Letter to Pat Delahanty "Kentucky Bill - SB 6", 2011 January 10
    - "A declaration of five principles to guide Utah's immigration discussion from a document entitled The Utah Compact", 2011 January 11
    - Senate Bill 6 Sample Letter to Law Enforcement and Elected Officials, 2011 January 11
    - Courier-Journal.com "Rep. Rick Rand says House Unlikely to pass Immigration Bill", 2011 January 12
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky State Fiscal Note Statement, 2011 January 13
    - Courier-Journal.com Article "Cash Express Donors Back both Beshear and Williams", 2011 January 14
    - Messenger-Inquirer.com "Groups Oppose Trespassing Bill", 2011 January 15
    - Bluegrass Politics Article "Horse Industry Could Suffer under Ky.'s Immigration Proposal", 2011 January 16
    - Kentucky.com "Keeling: Beshear Snub Political Savvy or a Mistake?", 2011 January 16
    - Messenger-Inquirer.com "Catholics Air Concerns to Elected Officials", 2011 January 16
    - Messenger-Inquirer.com "Senate Bill 6 not Fiscally Responsible", 2011 January 19
    - New text for Severely Mentally Ill Bill, 2011 January 20
    - Courier-Journal.com "Head Start Officials Warn on Immigration Bill", 2011 January 21
    - Kentucky.com "Latino Community Expresses Fear About Immigration Bill", 2011 January 24
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky Letter to Pastors/Parish Life Directors, 2011 January 24
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky "Catholic Pastors and Parish Life Leaders Urged to Push Passage of Senate Bill 9" Press Release, 2011 January 25
    - Catholics @ the Capitol Agenda, Covington Materials, 2011 January 29
    - Concerns Regarding House Bill 3, 2011 March 2
    - Arizona Catholic Conference "Arizona Bishops Express Concern About Legislation Targeting Undocumented Immigrants", 2010 March
    - Arizona Catholic Conference "Arizona Catholic Conference Bishops Statement on Legislation Impacting Vulnerable Populations", 2010 March
    - House Bill 16, Handout, 2010 April
    - 2010 Interim Legislative Record Newsletter, 2010 August
    - Article from Legislative Record Newsletter, 2010 August
    - KY Forward Agenda, Draft, 2010 September
    - Letter Invitation to Catholics @ the Capitol 2010-2011: Faithful Citizenship in the Archdiocese of Louisville, 2010 October
    - Center for American Progress "Stop the Conference: The Economic and Fiscal Consequences of Conference Cancellations Due to Arizona's S.B. 1070", 2010 November
    - Payday Loana "Modern Day Usury: The Payday Loan Trap, A Discussion Guide for Churches", 2010 November